TYRION LANNISTER: We have suffered at each other's hands.
提利昂·兰尼斯特：我们彼此都在受苦。
We have lost people we love at each other's hands.
我们失去了彼此相爱的人。
(DRAGON SCREECHING)
（龙尖叫）
JAIME LANNISTER: This isn't about noble houses,
杰米·兰尼斯特：这不是关于贵族住宅，
this is about the living and the dead.
这是关于活着的和死去的。
And I intend to stay amongst the living.
我打算留在这里。
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
（戏剧音乐演奏）
DAENERYS TARGARYEN: I offer you a choice.
丹妮莉丝：我给你一个选择。
Bend the knee and join me,
弯曲膝盖和我一起，
or refuse, and die.
或者拒绝，然后死去。
(MEN YELLING)
（男人大喊大叫）
She is here to reclaim the Seven Kingdoms.
她来这里是为了夺回七国。
The North is one of those seven kingdoms.
北方是那七个王国之一。
JON SHOW: The Night King's army grows larger by the day.
乔恩秀：国王的军队一天比一天大。
(YELLING)
（大喊大叫）
We need allies. Powerful allies.
我们需要盟友。强大的盟友。
(WIGHT SCREECHES)
（尖锐的尖叫声）
CERSEI LANNISTER: The monsters are real.
塞西·兰尼斯特：怪物是真的。
Dragons, White Walkers, Dothraki screamers...
龙，白色步行者，多斯拉克尖叫者…
Let the monsters kill each other.
让怪物互相残杀。
We will deal with whatever is left.
我们会处理剩下的一切。
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
（音乐增强）
DAENERYS: We are going to destroy the Night King
丹妮莉斯：我们要摧毁夜王
and his army, and we'll do it together.
和他的军队，我们一起做。
SANSA STARK: He pledged to fight for Daenerys Targaryen.
桑萨·斯塔克：他发誓要为丹妮莉丝·塔格利安而战。
He's bent the knee.
他膝盖弯曲了。
BRANDON STARK: He needs to know the truth.
布兰登·斯塔克：他需要知道真相。
Jon isn't really my father's son.
乔恩不是我父亲的儿子。
He's the son of Rhaegar Targaryen,
他是瑞加·塔格利安的儿子，
and my aunt, Lyanna Stark.
还有我的姑妈，莉安娜·斯塔克。
He's the heir to the Iron Throne.
他是铁王座的继承人。
We need to tell him.
我们需要告诉他。
JON SNOW: The same thing is coming for all of us...
乔恩·斯诺：同样的事情也会发生在我们所有人身上……
And it is here.
它就在这里。
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
（音乐渐弱）
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[PANTING]
[喘气]
[PIG SQUEALS]
[猪尖叫声]
[DONKEY BRAYS]
驴brays [ ]
[CHICKENS SQUAWKING]
squawking [鸡]
[MARCHING]
[行进]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[男人们模糊不清地叫喊]
[HORSES SNORTING]
[马呼噜声]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[马嘶声]
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[马嘶]
You should consider yourself lucky.
你应该认为自己很幸运。
At least your balls won't freeze off.
至少你的球不会结冰。
VARYS: You take great offense at dwarf jokes,
瓦里斯：你对侏儒笑话很生气，
but love telling eunuch jokes. Why is that?
但喜欢讲太监的笑话。为什么会这样？
Because I have balls, and you don't.
因为我有球，而你没有。
I warned you.
我警告过你。
Northerners don't much trust outsiders.
北方人不太信任外来人。
[DRAGON ROARS]
[龙吼]
[PEOPLE CLAMORING]
[人们吵闹]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[DRAGONS ROARING]
[龙怒吼]
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
[女人尖叫]
[HORSES NEIGHING]
[马嘶鸣]
[ROARS]
[Roars]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[呼吸沉重]
Look at you.
看看你。
[SNIFFLES]
[Sinfles]
You're a man.
你是个男人。
Almost.
几乎。
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
JON: Where's Arya? -Lurking somewhere.
乔恩：雅利安在哪里？-潜伏在某个地方。
JON: Queen Daenerys of House Targaryen.
乔恩：塔格利安家族的戴纳瑞斯女王。
My sister, Sansa Stark, the Lady of Winterfell.
我的妹妹，桑萨·斯塔克，温特弗尔夫人。
Thank you for inviting us into your home, Lady Stark.
谢谢你邀请我们到你家，斯塔克夫人。
The North is as beautiful
北方也很美
as your brother claimed, as are you.
正如你哥哥所说，你也是。
Winterfell is yours, Your Grace.
冬之城是你的，陛下。
We don't have time for all this.
我们没有时间做这些。
The Night King has your dragon. He's one of them now.
夜王有你的龙。他现在是其中之一。
The Wall has fallen,
墙倒了，
the dead march south.
死路往南走。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
SANSA: As soon as we heard about the Wall,
桑萨：我们一听说那堵墙，
I called all our banners to retreat to Winterfell.
我打电话给所有的横幅，让他们撤退到冬城。
Lord Umber...
Umber勋爵…
when can we expect your people to arrive?
我们预计你们的人什么时候到？
We need more horses and wagons, if it please my lady.
我们需要更多的马和马车，如果我的夫人高兴的话。
And my lord.
我的主。
And my queen. Sorry.
还有我的皇后。对不起的。
SANSA: You'll have as many as we can spare.
桑萨：你会有我们能提供的尽可能多的。
Hurry back to Last Hearth and bring your people here.
快点回到最后一个壁炉，把你们的人带到这里来。
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
We need to send ravens to the Night's Watch as well.
我们还需要送乌鸦去守夜。
There's no sense in manning the castles anymore.
再也没有必要为城堡配备人手了。
We make our stand here.
我们站在这里。
At once, Your Grace.
立刻，陛下。
"Your Grace."
“陛下。”
But you're not. Are you?
但你不是。你是吗？
You left Winterfell a king
你离开了一个国王
and came back a--
然后回来了--
I'm not sure what you are now.
我不知道你现在是谁。
[PEOPLE MURMURING] LYANNA: A lord?
[人们喃喃自语]莉安娜：上帝？
Nothing at all?
什么都没有？
-It's not important. LYANNA: Not important?
-这不重要。莉安娜：不重要吗？
We named you King in the North.
我们把你命名为北方的国王。
[PEOPLE EXCLAIMING]
[人们惊叹]
MAN: King of the North!
男人：北方之王！
You did, my lady.
是的，夫人。
It was the honor of my life.
这是我一生的荣誉。
I'll always be grateful for your faith.
我将永远感激你的信仰。
But when I left Winterfell,
但当我离开冬天的时候，
I told you we need allies or we will die.
我告诉过你我们需要盟友，否则我们会死的。
I have brought those allies home
我把那些盟友带回家了
to fight alongside us.
和我们并肩作战。
I had a choice,
我有一个选择，
keep my crown or protect the North.
保留我的王冠或保护北方。
I chose the North.
我选择了北方。
[PEOPLE MURMURING]
[人们喃喃自语]
If anyone survives the war to come,
如果有人能在即将到来的战争中幸存，
we'll have Jon Snow to thank.
我们要感谢乔恩·斯诺。
He risked his life to show us the threat is real.
他冒着生命危险向我们表明威胁是真实的。
Thanks to his courage,
多亏了他的勇气，
we have brought with us the greatest army
我们带来了最伟大的军队
the world has ever seen.
世界从未见过。
We have brought two full-grown dragons.
我们带来了两只成年龙。
And soon, the Lannister army
很快，兰尼斯特军队
will ride north to join our cause.
将北上加入我们的事业。
[PEOPLE GRUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地抱怨]
I know, I know, our people
我知道，我知道，我们的人民
haven't been friends in the past.
以前不是朋友。
But we must fight together now...
但我们现在必须一起战斗…
or die.
或死亡。
May I ask, how are we meant to feed
我能问一下，我们打算怎么吃饭吗？
the greatest army the world has ever seen?
世界上最伟大的军队？
While I ensured our stores would last through winter,
虽然我保证我们的商店能持续到冬天，
I didn't account for Dothraki,
我没有解释多斯拉克，
Unsullied and two full-grown dragons.
无污染的和两条成年龙。
What do dragons eat, anyway?
不管怎样，龙吃什么？
Whatever they want.
不管他们想要什么。
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[马嘶]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
Hey, careful, lads. We need every last bit of it.
嘿，小心点，伙计们。我们需要最后一点。
MAN 1: Sorry 'bout that.
男1：对不起。
Are these the last of the wagons?
这是最后一辆车吗？
MAN 2: Aye.
男2：是的。
GENDRY: All right, let's get it all to the forges.
詹德利：好吧，让我们把一切都交给锻造厂吧。
My lord.
大人。
My lady.
我的夫人。
The Lady of Winterfell.
温特弗尔夫人。
Has a nice ring to it.
有一枚漂亮的戒指。
So does Hand of the Queen.
女王之手也是。
Depending on the queen, I suppose.
我想这取决于女王。
Last time we spoke was at Joffrey's wedding.
我们上次谈话是在乔弗里的婚礼上。
-Miserable affair. -It had its moments.
-悲惨的事情。-它有它的时刻。
Apologies for leaving like that.
为这样离开道歉。
Yes, it was a bit hard to explain
是的，有点难解释
why my wife fled moments after the king's murder.
为什么我妻子在国王被杀后不久就逃跑了？
We both survived.
我们都活了下来。
Many underestimated you.
很多人低估了你。
Most of them are dead now.
他们大多数人现在都死了。
I'm sure you weren't thrilled to hear
我相信你听到这消息一定不高兴
the Lannister army's marching north.
兰尼斯特军队向北行进。
You have every right to be fearful of my sister.
你有权利害怕我妹妹。
No one fears her more than I do.
没有人比我更害怕她。
-But I promise, you'll be safe-- -Cersei told you her army
-但我保证，你会安全的——瑟曦告诉过你她的军队
was coming north to fight for you?
是来北方为你而战吗？
She did.
她做到了。
And you believed her?
你相信她？
She has something to live for now.
她现在有东西要活。
I believe she wants to survive.
我相信她想活下来。
I used to think you were the cleverest man alive.
我以前以为你是世上最聪明的人。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
ARYA: You used to be taller.
雅利安：你以前更高了。
JON: How did you sneak up on me?
乔恩：你是怎么偷袭我的？
How did you survive a knife through the heart?
你是怎么从心脏里钻出来的？
I didn't.
我没有。
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
-[SIGHS] -[SCOFFS]
-[叹息]—[嘲笑]
You still have it.
你仍然拥有它。
Needle.
针头
Have you ever used it?
你用过吗？
Once or twice.
一次或两次。
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
Valyrian steel.
瓦利安钢
Jealous?
嫉妒？
[SCOFFS] Too heavy for me.
[嘲笑]对我来说太重了。
Where were you before?
你以前在哪里？
I could've used your help with Sansa.
我可以利用你对桑萨的帮助。
She doesn't like your queen, does she?
她不喜欢你的女王，是吗？
Sansa thinks she's smarter than everyone.
桑萨认为她比所有人都聪明。
She's the smartest person I've ever met.
她是我见过的最聪明的人。
Now you're defending her?
现在你在为她辩护？
[CHUCKLES] You?
[笑]你？
I'm defending our family.
我在保卫我们的家庭。
So is she.
她也是。
[SOFTLY] Yeah.
[温柔地]是的。
[NORMALLY] I'm her family too.
[通常]我也是她的家人。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
Don't forget that.
别忘了。
Your Grace, I'm afraid I bring terrible news.
陛下，恐怕我带来了可怕的消息。
The dead have broken through the Wall.
死者已穿墙而入。
Good.
很好。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
Why don't you just get it over with and kill me?
你为什么不把它拿过来杀了我？
[SIGHS] But we're family.
[叹息]但我们是一家人。
The last Greyjoys left in the world.
世界上最后的欢乐。
[GRUNTS SOFTLY]
温柔的[人]
The last ones with balls anyway.
最后一个带球的。
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
If I kill you...
如果我杀了你…
who can I talk to?
我能和谁说话？
Hmm?
隐马尔可夫模型？
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
I've got a crew full of mutes.
我有一队人都是哑巴。
It gets lonely at sea.
它在海上变得孤独。
Are we in King's Landing?
我们是在国王的平台上吗？
Mm.
毫米。
You picked the losing side.
你选择了失败的一面。
Then I'll sail the Iron Fleet somewhere else.
那我就去别的地方坐船出海。
But first I'm gonna fuck the queen.
但首先我要和女王做爱。
[FOOTSTEPS LEAVING]
[脚步声离开]
[PANTING]
[喘气]
[DOOR OPENS, THEN CLOSES]
[门打开，然后关闭]
CERSEI: Twenty-thousand men, is it?
瑟曦：两万人，是吗？
Yes, Your Grace. A few died in transit.
是的，陛下。一些人在运输途中死亡。
They cheated at dice.
他们掷骰子作弊。
Or maybe I cheated.
或者我作弊了。
Someone cheated.
有人作弊了。
They weren't good fighters. You won't miss them.
他们不是好战士。你不会错过他们的。
-Horses? -Two thousand.
-马？-二千。
And elephants?
大象呢？
HARRY: Uh, no elephants, Your Grace.
哈利：呃，没有大象，陛下。
That's disappointing.
真令人失望。
I was told the Golden Company had elephants.
我听说黄金公司有大象。
HARRY: They are excellent beasts, Your Grace,
哈利：他们是很好的野兽，陛下，
but not well-suited to long sea voyages.
但不太适合长途海上航行。
In any event, you are most welcome
无论如何，我们都欢迎你
here in King's Landing, Captain Strickland.
斯特里克兰上尉，在国王的降落处。
We look forward to fighting on your behalf, Your Grace.
我们期待着为您而战，陛下。
EURON: Am I most welcome here?
欧龙：这里最欢迎我吗？
You are a true friend of the crown
你是皇上的真正朋友
and an honored guest.
还有一位尊贵的客人。
EURON: Good.
尤伦：很好。
As a true friend and an honored guest...
作为真正的朋友和尊贵的客人…
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
[WHISPERS] I was hoping we could talk in private.
我希望我们能私下谈谈。
After the war. That was our agreement.
战后。那是我们的协议。
Wars sometimes last years.
战争有时持续数年。
You want a whore, buy one.
你要一个妓女，买一个。
You want a queen...
你想要一个女王…
earn her.
赢得她。
How?
怎么用？
I've given her justice,
我给了她正义，
an army and the Iron Fleet,
一支军队和一支钢铁舰队，
yet she gives me no sign of affection.
但她没有给我任何爱的迹象。
My heart is nearly broken.
我的心几乎要碎了。
You're insolent.
你太傲慢了。
-I've executed men for less. -They were lesser men.
-我以更少的代价处决了人。-他们是地位较低的人。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
DIRAH: I hear the dragon burnt up a thousand Lannister men.
狄拉：我听说龙烧死了一千个兰尼斯特人。
CRAYA: Burnt up some of my favorite boys.
把我最喜欢的几个男孩都烧死了。
DIRAH: Archie, was it? -And William.
迪拉：阿奇，是吗？-还有威廉。
-Tall handsome William? -Yeah, tall handsome William.
-高大英俊的威廉？-是的，高大英俊的威廉。
They said what's left of him could fit in a wine glass.
他们说他剩下的可以放在酒杯里。
I am the only man you ever met who shot a dragon.
我是你见过的唯一射杀龙的人。
-Did you? BRONN: Nearly killed it.
-是吗？布朗恩：差点就杀了它。
That's brave.
那是勇敢的。
[MOANING SOFTLY]
[ moaning softly ]
[BRONN SIGHS]
[布隆叹气]
CRAYA: That boy Eddie... DIRAH: The ginger?
craya：那男孩埃迪…dirah：姜？
That's him. Came back with his face burnt right off.
那就是他。回来的时候脸马上就烧了。
He's got no eyelids now.
他现在没有眼睑了。
How does he sleep with no eyelids?
他怎么睡得没眼皮？
All right, can we stop talking about the fucking dragons now?
好吧，我们现在可以停止谈论那些该死的龙了吗？
QYBURN: Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
Qyburn：黑水镇的布朗恩爵士。
You're kidding me.
你在开玩笑。
Apologies for the interruption,
抱歉打扰了，
but the queen did urge me to hurry.
但女王确实敦促我快点。
Sorry, ladies.
对不起，女士们。
Another time perhaps.
也许下次吧。
You ever get lonely, I am partial to older gentlemen.
你一个人孤单，我就偏袒老先生。
Poor girl. The pox will take her within the year.
可怜的女孩。天花会在一年内夺走她的生命。
[COUGHS]
[咳嗽]
-Which girl? QYBURN: The queen's brothers
-哪个女孩？女王的兄弟
made promises to you and broke them.
向你许下承诺，然后违背了承诺。
Her Grace wants to rectify their mistake.
她的恩典想纠正他们的错误。
She once gave me a castle and a wife,
她曾经给我一座城堡和一个妻子，
then rectified me right out of them.
然后马上纠正我。
That was Ser Jaime's doing, not hers.
那是杰米爵士干的，不是她的。
When Queen Cersei wants something,
当瑟曦女王想要什么的时候，
she pays in advance and in gold.
她预付金。
Several chests of it, in fact.
事实上，它有好几箱。
Waiting for you in a wagon just outside.
在外面的马车里等你。
So she wants to murder someone, but she can't send her soldiers.
所以她想谋杀某人，但她不能派遣她的士兵。
If it's the Dragon Queen she's after...
如果她要找的是龙皇后…
She has other plans for the Targaryen girl.
她对塔格利安女孩还有别的打算。
Yeah, well, good luck with that.
是的，好吧，祝你好运。
Our queen's brothers are unlikely
我们女王的兄弟不太可能
to survive their Northern adventures.
为了生存他们的北方冒险。
But in the event that they do...
但如果他们这样做…
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
She has a keen sense of poetic justice.
她有强烈的诗意正义感。
That fucking family.
那个该死的家庭。
QYBURN: When the Citadel expelled me,
当城堡驱逐我时，
I thought I would die poor and alone,
我以为我会孤独地死去，
but in exchange for my service, Queen Cersei made me her Hand.
但是作为对我服务的交换，瑟曦女王让我做了她的手。
What would she do for the man
她会为那个男人做什么
who rids her of her treasonous brothers?
谁能使她摆脱叛国的兄弟？
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[DOOR OPENS, THEN CLOSES]
[门打开，然后关闭]
[SIGHS] I wanted those elephants.
[叹息]我想要那些大象。
[EURON SIGHS]
[欧隆叹息]
So...
所以…
how do I compare to the fat king?
我该怎么和胖国王比较呢？
You're insulting my late husband?
你在侮辱我已故的丈夫？
Are you offended?
你生气了吗？
Robert had a different whore every night,
罗伯特每晚都有不同的妓女，
but he still didn't know his way around a woman's body.
但他仍然不知道如何绕过女人的身体。
And the Kingslayer?
那凶手呢？
You enjoy risking your neck, don't you?
你喜欢冒着脖子风险，是吗？
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
Life is boring.
生活是无聊的。
You're not boring, I'll give you that.
你不无聊，我会给你的。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
Do I please the queen?
我能取悦女王吗？
You might be the most arrogant man I've ever met.
你可能是我见过的最傲慢的人。
[WHISPERS] I like that.
我喜欢这样。
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
[NORMALLY] But now I want to be alone.
[通常]但现在我想一个人呆着。
[SIGHS SOFTLY]
[轻轻叹息]
[SOFTLY] I'm going to put a prince in your belly.
[轻轻地]我要把王子放在你肚子里。
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[关门]
[BOW STRING CREAKS]
[弓弦吱吱声]
[MEN GRUNTING]
[但是]的叫声
-[FLESH SQUELCHES] -[GASPS]
-[肌肉吱吱声]-[喘息声]
[PANTING]
[喘气]
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
[BOTH GRUNT]
[两个咕噜]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
YARA: Euron can't defend the Iron Islands,
雅拉：欧洲不能保卫铁岛，
not if he's in King's Landing with all his men and his ships.
如果他和他所有的人和船都在国王的平台上，那就不行了。
We can take our home back.
我们可以带回家。
Daenerys went north.
丹妮莉丝往北走。
Daenerys will need somewhere to retreat
丹妮莉斯需要退却
if they can't hold the North.
如果他们不能控制住北方。
Somewhere the dead can't go.
某个死人不能去的地方。
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[男人们模糊不清地叫喊]
You're my queen. I go where you command.
你是我的女王。我去你命令的地方。
You want to go to Winterfell.
你想去冬城。
To fight for the Starks.
为斯塔克家族而战。
Go.
去吧。
What is dead may never die.
死了的未必会死。
But kill the bastards anyway.
但还是杀了那些混蛋。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
WOLKAN: Welcome back, my lady.
沃坎：欢迎回来，夫人。
If you'd follow me...
如果你跟着我…
VARYS: The Karstarks.
karstarks瓦里斯：。
TYRION: One of the better sigils.
利昂：一个更好的印记。
Beats an onion, anyway.
不管怎么说，都比洋葱强。
Can't argue with that.
不能反驳。
Not so long ago, the Starks and the Karstarks
不久前，斯塔克一家和卡斯塔克一家
were slaughtering each other on the battlefield.
在战场上互相残杀。
Jon Snow brought peace to the houses.
乔恩·斯诺给房子带来了和平。
TYRION: And our queen is grateful.
提利昂：我们的女王很感激。
Her gratitude is lovely, but that's not my point.
她的感激是可爱的，但这不是我的意思。
The Northmen are loyal to Jon Snow, not to her.
北方人忠于乔恩·斯诺，而不是她。
They don't know her.
他们不认识她。
The Free Folk don't know her.
自由人不认识她。
I've been up here a while, and I'm telling you,
我在这里呆了一会儿，我告诉你，
they're stubborn as goats.
他们像山羊一样顽固。
You want their loyalty, you have to earn it.
你想要他们的忠诚，你必须去争取。
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
I sense that you're leading to a proposal.
我感觉你在提出一个建议。
A proposal is what I'm proposing.
我提议的就是一个提议。
On the off chance that we survive the Night King,
当我们在夜王中幸存的时候，
what if the Seven Kingdoms,
如果七国，
for once in their whole shit history,
在他们的整个狗屎历史上，
were ruled by a just woman and an honorable man?
是由一个公正的女人和一个可敬的男人统治的？
TYRION: They do make a handsome couple.
提利昂让他们英俊的夫妇。
VARYS: You overestimate our influence.
你高估了我们的影响力。
Jon and Daenerys don't want to listen to lonely old men.
乔恩和丹妮莉丝不想听孤独的老人们说。
I'm not that old.
我没那么老。
Not as old as him.
不像他那么老。
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
Our queen respects the wisdom of age.
我们的女王尊重时代的智慧。
Of course she does.
当然了。
Respect is how the young keep us at a distance,
尊重是年轻人与我们保持距离的方式，
so we don't remind them of an unpleasant truth.
所以我们不会让他们想起不愉快的事实。
TYRION: What is that?
提利昂：那是什么？
Nothing lasts.
没有什么是永恒的。
MAN: Hey!
你：嘿！
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[男人们模糊不清地叫喊]
Your sister doesn't like me.
你妹妹不喜欢我。
She doesn't know you.
她不认识你。
If it makes you feel any better,
如果它能让你感觉更好，
she didn't like me either when we were growing up.
我们长大后她也不喜欢我。
She doesn't need to be my friend...
她不需要做我的朋友…
but I am her queen.
但我是她的女王。
If she can't respect me...
如果她不尊重我…
[MAN SPEAKS DOTHRAKI INDISTINCTLY]
[男人说话含糊不清]
[IN DOTHRAKI]
[多斯拉克]
What's the matter?
怎么了
[IN ENGLISH] The dragons are barely eating.
[英语]龙很少吃东西。
[DRAGONS GROWLING SOFTLY]
[龙轻轻地咆哮]
JON: What's wrong with them?
乔恩：他们怎么了？
They don't like the North.
他们不喜欢北方。
Go on.
继续。
I don't know how to ride a dragon.
我不知道怎么骑龙。
Nobody does. Until they ride a dragon.
没有人会这样做。直到他们骑着龙。
What if he doesn't want me to?
如果他不想我怎么办？
Then I've enjoyed your company, Jon Snow.
我很喜欢你的陪伴，乔恩·斯诺。
[SCOFFS]
（嘲笑）
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
What do I hold onto?
我能抓住什么？
Whatever you can.
尽你所能。
-[DRAGON CHITTERS] -[JON GRUNTS]
-[龙怪]-[乔恩咕哝]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
[JON YELPS]
[乔恩吠声]
[YELLS]
[叫喊]
JON: Aah!
乔恩：啊！
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[吹口哨]
You've completely ruined horses for me.
你完全毁了我的马。
[LAUGHS]
[笑]
We could stay a thousand years...
我们可以留下一千年…
no one would find us.
没有人会找到我们。
We'd be pretty old.
我们会很老的。
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
It's cold up here for a southern girl.
这里对一个南方女孩来说很冷。
So keep your queen warm.
所以让你的女王暖和一点。
[DROGON GROWLS SOFTLY]
[Drogon轻声咆哮]
Don't be afraid.
别害怕。
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
【exhales sharply ]
MAN 1: That's good.
男1：很好。
[MAN 1 SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
[男1说话含糊不清]
[HAMMER CLANKING]
[锤子叮当声]
MAN 2: Gendry? MAN 3: He's here.
男人2：GeDRY？男3：他来了。
It isn't easy making a blade that big with dragonglass.
用龙钳做这么大的刀刃不容易。
You're saying you're good, is that it?
你是说你很好，是吗？
I'm just saying it's a tricky material to--
我只是说这是一个棘手的材料--
You know who makes weapons for the wildlings?
你知道谁为野人制造武器吗？
Cripples and cocksuckers.
残废和吸食公鸡。
-Which one are you? ARYA: Leave him be.
-你是哪一个？雅利安：别理他。
I heard you were here.
我听说你在这里。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
You left me to die.
你让我去死。
First I robbed you.
首先我抢了你。
You're a cold little bitch, aren't you?
你是个冷酷的小婊子，不是吗？
Guess that's why you're still alive.
这就是为什么你还活着。
That was a nice ax you made for him.
你为他做的斧头真漂亮。
You've gotten better.
你已经好多了。
Yeah, thanks. So have you.
是的，谢谢。你也一样。
I mean, you look good.
我是说，你看起来不错。
Thanks. So do you.
谢谢。你也是。
It's not a bad place to grow up, if it wasn't so cold.
如果天气不那么冷的话，这不是一个成长的好地方。
Stay close to that forge, then.
那就靠近那家锻炉吧。
-Is that a command, Lady Stark? -Don't call me that.
-这是命令吗，斯塔克夫人？-别这么叫我。
As you wish, milady.
如你所愿，夫人。
[MAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
[男人说话含糊不清]
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
ARYA: Here's my wish.
雅利安：这是我的愿望。
Can you make it?
你能做到吗？
What do you need something like this for?
你需要这样的东西做什么？
Can you make it or not?
你能不能成功？
You already have a sword. What's that?
你已经有一把剑了。那是什么？
It's Valyrian steel.
这是瓦雷利钢铁公司。
I always knew you were just another rich girl.
我一直都知道你只是另一个有钱的女孩。
[MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
[男人含糊不清地喊道]
You don't know any other rich girls.
你不认识其他有钱的女孩。
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[敲门]
Come in.
进来。
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[关门]
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
Lord Glover wishes us good fortune,
格洛弗勋爵祝我们好运，
but he's staying in Deepwood Motte with his men.
但他和他的部下呆在深木的座右铭里。
"House Glover will stand behind House Stark
“豪斯格洛弗会站在斯塔克后面
as we have for a thousand years."
我们已经有一千年了。”
Isn't that what he said?
他不是这么说的吗？
SANSA: "I will stand behind Jon Snow," he said.
桑萨：“我会站在乔恩·斯诺后面，”他说。
"The King in the North."
“北方的国王。”
I told you we needed allies.
我告诉过你我们需要盟友。
SANSA: You didn't tell me you were going to abandon your crown.
桑萨：你没有告诉我你要放弃你的王冠。
I never wanted a crown.
我从不想要王冠。
All I wanted was to protect the North.
我只想保护北方。
I brought two armies home with me, two dragons.
我带了两支军队回家，两条龙。
And a Targaryen queen.
还有一个塔格利安女王。
[SIGHS] Do you think
你觉得呢
we can beat the Army of the Dead without her?
没有她我们就能打败死人？
I fought them, Sansa. Twice.
我和他们战斗过，桑萨。两次。
You want to worry about who holds what title,
你要担心谁拥有什么头衔，
I'm telling you it doesn't matter.
我告诉你这没关系。
Without her, we don't stand a chance.
没有她，我们就没有机会。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
Do you have any faith in me at all?
你对我有信心吗？
You know I do.
你知道的。
She'll be a good queen.
她会成为一个好皇后的。
For all of us.
对我们所有人来说。
She's not her father.
她不是她父亲。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
No, she's much prettier.
不，她更漂亮。
[SCOFFS]
（嘲笑）
Did you bend the knee to save the North
你屈膝拯救北方了吗
or because you love her?
还是因为你爱她？
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[男人们模糊不清地叫喊]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[清喉咙]
Oh!
哦！
So you're the man?
你就是那个人？
Um...
嗯。。。
Which man am I, Your Grace?
我是谁，陛下？
The one who saved Ser Jorah when no one else could.
当别人都救不了乔拉爵士的人。
They could, they just wouldn't.
他们可以，只是不会。
DAENERYS: I'll have to make some changes
丹妮莉斯：我得做些改变
in the Citadel when I take my throne.
当我登上王位的时候。
A great service merits a great reward.
一项伟大的服务值得奖赏。
SAMWELL: Oh, it's my honor to serve you, Your Grace.
山姆韦尔：噢，我很荣幸为您效劳，陛下。
DAENERYS: Well, there must be something I could give you.
丹妮莉斯：嗯，一定有什么我可以给你的。
If it's not too much trouble,
如果不是太麻烦，
I could use a pardon.
我可以请你原谅。
For what crime?
什么罪？
Um--
-嗯
I borrowed a few books from the Citadel.
我从城堡借了几本书。
And also a sword.
还有一把剑。
-From the Citadel? SAMWELL: From my family.
-从城堡来的？萨姆韦尔：我的家人。
It's been in House Tarly for generations.
它在家里呆了好几代。
It would've been mine anyway, eventually,
不管怎么说，它最终会是我的，
but my father had other ideas.
但我父亲有其他想法。
Not Randyll Tarly?
不是兰德尔·塔利吗？
You know him?
你认识他吗？
I offered to let him retain his lands and titles
我提议让他保留他的土地和头衔
if he bent the knee.
如果他弯曲膝盖。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
DAENERYS: He refused.
他拒绝了。
[GULPS]
[大口]
Well...
好。。。
At least I'll be allowed home again,
至少我可以回家了，
now that my brother's the lord.
既然我哥哥是上帝。
Your brother stood with your father.
你哥哥和你父亲站在一起。
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[呼吸颤抖]
Hm.
嗯。
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢，陛下。
For telling me.
告诉我。
And m--
和M——
-May I...? -Of course.
-我可以……-当然。
[DOOR CLOSES]
[关门]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[呼吸沉重]
[SNIFFLES]
[Sinfles]
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[马嘶]
[WHIMPERS]
呜咽声
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
SAMWELL: What are you doing out here?
萨姆韦尔：你在这里干什么？
Waiting, for an old friend.
等待，等待一位老朋友。
It's time to tell Jon the truth.
是时候告诉乔恩真相了。
No, no.
不，不。
You're his brother. Shouldn't you tell him?
你是他的兄弟。你不应该告诉他吗？
I'm not his brother.
我不是他的兄弟。
He trusts you more than anyone.
他比任何人都更信任你。
Now's the time.
现在是时候了。
[JON SIGHS]
[乔恩叹息]
[MAN GRUNTING, THUDS]
[男人咕哝，砰砰声]
[MAN GROANING]
groaning [人]
JON: Sam?
乔恩：山姆？？？？？？？
I'm sorry, I know I'm not supposed to be down here.
对不起，我知道我不应该在这里。
-Were you hiding from me? -Of course not.
-你在躲避我吗？当然不是。
What are you doing in Winterfell?
你在冬天干什么？
Or did you read every book in the Citadel already?
或者你已经读过城堡里的每本书了吗？
What's wrong?
发生了什么？
Gilly? Is she all right?
Gilly？她没事吧？
-She's good. -Little Sam?
-她很好。- Little Sam？
Don't you know?
你不知道吗？
Know what?
知道什么？
Daenerys...
Daenerys…
she executed my father and brother.
她处决了我的父亲和兄弟。
They were her prisoners.
他们是她的囚犯。
She didn't tell you.
她没有告诉你。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
We need to end this war.
我们需要结束这场战争。
Would you have done it?
你会这样做吗？
Well, I've executed men who disobeyed me.
嗯，我处决了不服从我的人。
SAMWELL: You've also spared men.
萨姆威尔：你也救过男人。
Thousands of wildlings when they refused to kneel.
成千上万的野人拒绝跪下。
I wasn't a king.
我不是国王。
But you were.
但你是。
You've always been.
你一直都是。
I gave up my crown, Sam.
我放弃了我的王冠，山姆。
I bent the knee.
我弯曲膝盖。
I'm not King in the North anymore.
我不再是北方的国王了。
I'm not talking about the King in the North.
我不是说北方的国王。
I'm talking about the King of the bloody Seven Kingdoms.
我说的是血腥七国之王。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
Bran and I worked it out.
布兰和我一起解决了。
I had a High Septon's diary. Bran had...
我有一本高中生的日记。布兰有…
whatever Bran has.
不管布兰有什么。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Your mother...
你母亲…
was Lyanna Stark.
是莉安娜·斯塔克。
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
【exhales sharply ]
SAMWELL: And your father...
萨姆威尔：你父亲……
your real father
你的亲生父亲
was Rhaegar Targaryen.
是雷加·坦格利安
You've never been a bastard.
你从来都不是混蛋。
You're Aegon Targaryen, true heir to the Iron Throne.
你是埃贡·塔格利安，铁王座的真正继承人。
I'm sorry, I know it's a lot to take in.
对不起，我知道这很难接受。
My father was the most honorable man I ever met.
我父亲是我见过的最可敬的人。
You're saying he lied to me all my life.
你是说他一辈子都在骗我。
No.
不。
Your father-- Well, Ned Stark.
你父亲——好吧，奈德·斯塔克。
He promised your mother he'd always protect you.
他答应过你妈妈他会一直保护你。
And he did. Robert would have murdered you if he knew.
他做到了。如果罗伯特知道的话，他会杀了你的。
You're the true king.
你是真正的国王。
Aegon Targaryen, Sixth of His Name,
埃贡·塔格利安，他的第六个名字，
Protector of the Realm, all of it.
王国的保护者，所有的一切。
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[呼吸颤抖]
-Daenerys is our queen. SAMWELL: She shouldn't be.
-丹妮莉丝是我们的女王。她不应该这样。
-That's treason. -It's the truth.
-那是叛国。-这是事实。
You gave up your crown to save your people.
你为了拯救你的人民而放弃了你的王冠。
Would she do the same?
她也会这么做吗？
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[脚步声接近]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[FOOTSTEPS GROWING LOUDER]
[脚步声越来越大]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[所有尖叫]
Stay back, he's got blue eyes!
别动，他有蓝眼睛！
I've always had blue eyes!
我一直有蓝眼睛！
[SIGHING]
[叹息]
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
Did you find anyone?
你找到谁了吗？
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
EDD: The Umber boy.
艾迪：棕色的男孩。
BERIC: It's a message.
贝里克：这是一个信息。
From the Night King.
来自夜王。
His army's between us and Winterfell. We're on foot.
他的军队在我们和冬城之间。我们走路去了。
We rode down from Castle Black.
我们从布莱克城堡骑马下来。
We can double up on the horses.
我们可以骑双倍的马。
If the horses last, we'll get there before the dead.
如果马匹能坚持下去，我们会在死前赶到那里。
We just have to hope
我们只是希望
the Night King doesn't come first.
夜王不是第一个来的。
-[SHRIEKING] -[MEN CLAMORING]
-[尖叫声]—[男人吵闹声]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[SHRIEKING STOPS]
shrieking [停止]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们含糊不清地交谈]
MAN: Keep moving! Straight up!
男人：继续走！笔直！
Stay together! Don't fall behind!
待在一起！不要落后！
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
DAENERYS: When I was a child, my brother would tell me
当我还是个孩子的时候，我哥哥会告诉我
a bedtime story, about the man who murdered our father.
睡前故事，关于谋杀我们父亲的人。
About all the things we would do to that man.
关于我们要对那个人做的一切。
You never should have trusted Cersei.
你不应该信任瑟曦。
You never should have either.
你也不应该这样。
ARYA STARK: Death...
艾丽娅·斯塔克：死亡…
it's got many faces, I look forward to seeing this one.
它有很多张脸，我期待着看到这张。
How long do we have?
我们有多长时间？
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
（尝试音乐播放）
TORMUND: Before the sun comes up tomorrow.
折磨：在明天太阳升起之前。
-(ARMY MARCHES, CLANKS) -♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
-（军队游行，叮当声）（戏剧音乐剧）